All right I have twelve thirty.
So, given that we are barely on the edge of the end of build twenty fifteen
...just march forward.
And, start sothank everybody really appreciate you coming out on friday afternoon to talk
about as...media services just by show hands of the folks in the room how many of you
are already very familiar or somewhat familiar with as...media services and the capabilities that we have
about three-quarters you that's great so you're
infer tree we have to sessions back-to-back talking about
are media services platforms part of asher I'm going to talk today about what's new in
the last several months...that we've added to the platform and then my colleague main
...after me and the following session about a deep dive on how
developers can begin quickly to use that so I hope you get to stay from both but if you don't I
think should be very enjoyable for all of us so let me introduce myself my name is martin wall
...a principle program manager in the as your media services product engineering
team and I have the distinct honor of having the role of global engagement manager
work with our customers and partners around the world trying to help them
...conundrum of how to use the cloud for streaming video
and media into their business and everyday applications and we've built
a pretty extensive and powerful platform that uses
are cloud infrastructure to deliver video to any device anywhere in the
world and I'm going to use a session to talk to-you about that capability how you can use that yourselves
...how you can develop with it I do want as
always remind everyone that it's always very vital and important for us to get your feedback on each of
these sessions and certainly...for help helping us to
plan what is important to you and what's valuable to-you for next year so please take the
opportunity to submit now evaluation online or after.
Here's what we're going to talk about in this session I'll give you a brief overview of what is as
you may services even though I did recognize that many of you raise your hand and
are and familiar with it I brought with me some great customer examples of some deployments that are already in the
market today and I'm going to try to show you what I can and,
walk you through them because the visual I mean this is media after all so if I do-too-much in powerpoint
...I'll probably...name so I brought that with me and then I'm going to talk about a
lot of the new stuff and there's been a lot of new stuff on this platform they've been great deal of
announcements a great deal feature ads and a lot of response and feedback that we've gotten the
last several years since we deployed this platform from our customers from you
...as to what we should be adding and how which enhance the platform someone walk through a lot of this
stuff in the course of the session but let me just back up and do a brief overview as a
...to what we're talking about here or talking about is the fact that we all know this to be the
fact that video is the way we all pretty much communicate on a regular basis whether
we're talking in our regular daily lies in terms of as consumers or whether we're talking about as employees
...videos the way that we all like to entertain ourselves be
entertained and communicate with our fellow colleagues and everyone has their
pocketed device some of you have three or more that are capable of playing
high motion high-definition video and you use them on a regular basis maybe you use them
to watching consumer on entertainment content maybe your company uses them to
entertain or educate and train you but,
these are these are the way of the world this is how we all work today and every company on the
planet...advantage of the fact that you can use streaming many media streaming video to
deliver this content but it's also gotten quite expensive we know that in order to provide
high-quality video everywhere you've got to have quite infrastructure to
support and what's more so is that while putting videos up on the internet
and sharing them with your friends colleagues and customers is not relatively new what is
becoming more and more new is the fact that we're doing a lot more live-streaming I hope some of you
...taken advantage of take a seeing that channel nine...been live-streaming this
conference on their web page and they've been doing that using the technology that we're talking about today in this room
measurement services as the cloud infrastructure to provide that and doing live-streaming
that can be challenging that can be hardness certainly can be very expensive but we think and
microsoft that the cloud infrastructure that we put together is precisely the kind of resource
that you is developers can use to help you drive new video streaming
applications whether they be around live or on-demand content so we built this platform called as
...media services and
it's based on the premise that you can take any content from any source anywhere whether be
...stream or would be recorded video that-you edit or create
a produce move into the cloud process in the cloud and then
distributed around the world to any device that can play video which for all intents
and purposes is every device of course you'll notice
that this is important to say that there are lots of different kinds of devices on
the planet between phones and tablets television sets and set-top boxes
pc's and smart tv's nearly everything can receive a stream
...video and nearly everything can display...so if your goal as a content owner is to
distribute your content to the widest audience possible and that's precisely what we've tried to do with
asher media services is to give you a cloud platform can very easily and
very cost-effectively get your video content anywhere you want without you having to
have the necessary...have to build the infrastructure yourself?
Now this platforms pretty broad
...widespread...not going to do a deep dive into each one of these areas
I want to point out with of course the entire flow from end-to-end from the point which
you submit a piece of content again I'm talking about content as
being both video file-based content or can be...stream content
...submit that to the cloud to any of the datacenters that are that are being operated around the world and
...allow the cloud to do the heavy lifting the encoding of that content the protection of that
content the streaming and distribution of that content and even the play
back of that content on to the devices that you want to hit this is what we mean when we say asher media
services this is a collection of resources at your disposal at the
developers disposal to take advantage of as you would any other resource that's running and
...today
...me services is just another part of the...are offering that we do today but
...specifically focus around video and video delivery now many companies around the planet
have taken advantage of this and they've developed application some of which you might be
familiar of using yourself maybe some of which are not but they use the cloud and
...cloud resources to create really cool applications
enable them to hit whatever their business needs are...recognize a bunch of these
but I thought I'd...a couple of...you might find even more recognizable so there
...little event that happened a couple of months ago let's just call it the
superbowl any football fans in the audience this year was brought to us by our broadcaster in
the united states nbc-and nbc sports and...did nbc want to do of course they want to
maximize the viewing audience and the superbowl now for years of course everyone's been
watching tv of the superbowl at home or within parties but of course more recently now
...the broadcasters...content owners have wanted to stream
...content to provide it to you on a mobile device that
wherever you are...going to the store to get more beer
...you going to refrigerator to pick up another beer or even taking a restroom break you don't have to
miss a single moment of the action so when we worked with nbc
to look at what could they do what could the cloud due to provide them with
the streaming platform they were very excited to be able to say hey it sounds to us the as
you're already has all this built all we have to do is bring the game to the cloud and the cloud
will bring the game to our viewers and that's precisely what they did nbc during the
superbowl on february stream the entire game including all of the
pre-game fun and post game fun and
streamed to all the devices that anyone can use in their hand
or at home to two-and-a-half-million people who watched at one point in
time...might not think that's a really high amount given that we know that the superbowl is one of the most watched
...events all year-long but last couple years that number of people who have watched
sporting events on devices has been increasing almost quadruple in year after
year after year last year it was only around sixty eight hundred-thousand viewers watched the super bowl on a
device and this year is two-point-five million that's pretty exciting
what's also exciting for us and microsoft is to notice the bit that said well,
you know, even though the superbowl...one of the highest most washed events of the year for us
is just another day at the office of the cloud...that was necessary to deliver the
superbowl the resources necessary to deliver the superbowl so that not a single-person who
tune into it would get spinning arrows are black screens or drop frame or bad
quality didn't even register as a blip on the infrastructure that we provide because this cloud
is pretty powerful now we don't expect everyone in this room to have a superbowl like
events on a daily basis but you can just
imagine the capabilities that are at your disposal if you want to do an event of this magnitude?
What was another event that we did last year well what is now
the most watched sporting events in all of a sports history that was
...four world cup in brazil last summer this event which of course
...seen by billions of people around the world was also streamed in this case by ten different
broadcasters around the world who use the asher cloud to also the distribute
the stream to a variety of different players in client apps that were built using
...services to deliver what's interesting about this is the broadcasters who did this didn't just want
to be experience of watching the game as you would on television set...now they want to
have a different experience they wanted...cloud to enhance the experience to
innovate so what about providing a synchronous data feed alongside the video
...feed that's time with the smart client...of pulling things like where are
the players on-the-field any given time and statistics around them or
maybe this one which some people love would love to be able to control the camera angles the
dasi when they're watching the game and watch the coach of the opposing team or the particular
star player or maybe a particular angle the smart clients
...viewers the capability of choosing the angle choosing the video stream that
was all traversing the actual media services cloud...network so
even though the game was being broadcast on one video stream you with the digital device
had choice of up to six or eight different have angles camera streams that you can take?
Now other companies around the world are deciding that, you know,
what I want to do is be able to deliver new programming to digital devices that I wouldn't be able to
do if I had to only do it by the cable or over the airwaves...satellite so
take fuji television network which is one of the largest broadcasters in japan they
...about two or three different broadcast channels but they have way more
programming and they can air on those terrestrial channels so what did they decide to do
what they decided to do was create a channel that stream's only
digital devices haven't over the top channel only in this case and
I'll...you bring show you an example of this because I think we can dial into japan
even while we're waiting here and see if it comes up of course it's around four or five in the morning
and in japan right now so one never really knows what japan is playing at any given time
books that they've got some music videos going on
this is a twenty four-hour channel that exists only out of the...
And, right-hander you can turn that down...give
...did...and...you get the idea this is just a broadcast channel but
it's a cloud broadcast channel and if you think about it I'm going to go ahead and turn that off.
If you think about it the world of television
is changing all of us can now be broadcasters all of us can now carry content that the
cloud distributes digital devices that might be an audience...the millions all around the world
...the our of cloud and if I told you that it only took five minutes
...channel like that can be delivered to millions of people
...might spin especially when you think about someone like oprah winfrey we spent about
eight hundred fifty million of her precious dollars to create her network and...about eighteen
months to do it so think about how revolutionary this technology can be in the hands of
very creative people which I know all of you are of course you to can become
a broadcaster of channels that are carried like fuji tv does and
they can be able to hit devices and really expand their audiences if
you travel to tokyo you talk to the folks and fuji as I have what they say is the whole next
generation of television watchers don't even watch tv on tv anymore I'm a
father teenage daughter and I certainly...the fact that I never see my daughter watching tv on the tv
all she sits in front of the tv with it on
or watching tv on her tablet I'm not quite sure what's going on there now another type of
use of this technology is for companies that themselves have content
rights but they don't have any broadcast or over-the-air rights themselves take a
company like ngos send this is a great example of a company that just purchased all of the rights to
...soccer leagues out of south america and europe and stream them to viewers here
in north america but they're not doing it with any physical infrastructure
whatsoever this is a entire television network that exists only in the
cloud...pretty outstanding
...amazing concept when you think about it and I have a sample of what this looks like to on my laptop here
...just switch over to that you can see it
...gsm dot com any of you can go to it and I think if you go soon they're still giving away about
a ninety-day free subscription so if...big fan of soccer you can watch any
game that might be happening at any time some of the games are live happening right now.
If irish fresh the screen.
We'll see if we can if we can see what's,
what's playing rate this very moment some of the games are
live of course some of the games are already in the past but the cool part of
this technology is you can be a viewer of soccer games even if you
are five thousand miles away so what you're watching right now is a live broadcast of
again going on right now being distributed only through the cloud
you cannot watch this content anywhere else and this technology that's doing
...of course is using one hundred-percent advertise technology this is very
exciting for the business owners of this business but it certainly also very
exciting problems consumers because if you're soccer fan,
you know, there's very limited ability get a lot of great european and american soccer here
...the us but here we have a services providing and I said if you
go right now you'll be able to get a free subscription so that's pretty cool.
Now how do the how do they do this you might ask.
Well, I told you they have no physical assets at all therefore everything that
they're doing is currently running in the cloud and this gives you a sense of the architecture
that's been used they send their streams from the venues of the soccer
where soccer's taking place all around the world they send them into the cloud
they ad commentary they encode them in the cloud they provide them
...distribute them via the cloud and they...through our content just delivery network or
...and to...all around
the us any type of device that you might be having in your pocket of course all the
other management services like building and subscriber management all being done in the cloud to using a combination of
technologies are probably already familiar with such as address
...and asher cash and api is not kind of thing.
This is an entire business they didn't exist before the cloud and is now hoping to be the next sort-of
as the ceo of ngos...it I want to be the next netflix of soccer?
Other types of applications using the cloud are pretty they're pretty numerous you can imagine that there are
companies around the planet that are doing things like I make digital post-production
I make commercials I make movies for a living and I'm going to use the clouds and distribute
and share my videos or maybe I do those hotel entertainment systems at some of us may
or may not still using these days certainly on cruise ships and other
...of hospitality industries where streaming video content is the way
...bring content around...out these days and if you have been an elevator or gas station and...
video screens that are there are not going to be just there anymore stores around the world
and outputting digital screens digital signage in their store and they're streaming video content through the
cloud so they can provide you real-time information about the products that, you know,
you want to buy a just talk to manufacture...one of those devices and he's added
motion textures so as you walk down the aisle with your cart at the grocery store video can play
to-you...that next hot boxes cereal that you really just have to try I know
the sounds a little minority report but is happening right now and the cloud is making it really easy
to deploy it and also in the enterprise I certainly no it's true that
...microsoft make us watch a lot of videos about how to interact with you guys and,
behave ourselves but companies around the planet use the cloud and streaming video to train
and educate their employees so...building video portals,
portals that are just webpages enable you to host videos some of those
...might be live and some of videos might be pre-recorded...them using the cloud the
...has so many different applications so many different things that you could be doing with it, for example,
in the medical field I learned recently about a live-streaming of
surgeries that took place a big events and medical industry
where doctors and surgeons around the world from ten different hospitals all put a camera in the
...or surgery room and shared by surgery so they can train and talk to each other
via the cloud how quickly wasn't to do this about ten minutes and
loan miniature camera that they hooked up to their laptop beaming
...six signal to the cloud allowing the cloud to do all the heavy work all they had to...share
their colleagues the web page where...could be found and already mentioned the ability for
you to create your own enterprise solution if you peel underneath that what you see
is that as I've been talking about all this functionality is exposed to you are developers through
...api so as companies around the planet try to decide what's the best thing that they can
do what are their goals objectives that they want to use the cloud for we've provided a
really powerful api to make it possible very easy and very quickly api
is enable you to go from a video that sits locally on your desktop to a
...nappy streamed any device anywhere on the planet so with that
...idea of some ideas of how some customers and some of our partners
are using this technology let's look at some of the new stuff that we've added the platform that's made all
of this possible.
The first thing I want to show you is the fact that I know many of you are developers and
newman if you love to code but if you happen to be a kind
of type who wants to look for a very quick and dirty way to get one of these applications up and
running what we've created a tool for you that you just gotta half it's called the
...media services explore and I highly recommend you take a look at this tool because this does
all the api work that you would otherwise have to do built into the tool going to show you what the
to looks like...real-time so-you can take a look at it and how it how it works?
This is the tool running on my windows
eight laptop here download it from that website and
what allows me to do is do everything that I've just been talking about every functionality imagine
...services built into a desktop tool so if I want to say, for example, go up
here and...piece of video content that's running on might that's I have local...like this
...hollow lenz video that was just published yesterday which I just picked up
I go and...locally and now I'm just going to push into the cloud and the tool do that for me
is writing into my blob storage account forming that's all I had to do very...of course you could
done that through...api running a visual studio but this tool...the time
inherit is stored in my in not in my account now once that
video now exists I might want to encoded might want encoded so that it can
be pliable on any device in the planet how do I do that of course there's an api for that
...also use the desktop tool just to go encode the asset with our cloud based
media encoder once I choose that gives me all the choices for different ways that I might
want to encoded but I want this to be encoded...adaptive
...streaming I want to be...with seven twenty
pi resolution so I'll just go and launch based on the default setting
and it starts kicking off a job it...jobs in the cloud for me of course using
api do that the tool takes that place and then job is going to start and I've
got a cloud based encoder that's running will pick up that encode
...video file that's going to take about three or four minutes to work
rather than make you wait around and wait for that I already got one
...earlier it's right here this is the encoded version now what you'll see of
courses that I defaults edit so it would create a different bit rates that's different
but rates for different devices depending on what network you happen to be on?
And, then once I've encoded I'm just going publish it by creating a
...a streaming url locate or...try that one more time.
Publish.
Create low cuter again.
So,...care defaults to a year from now that's plenty fine
...create that what it's doing now is it's pushing, pushing a url out so
that I can now give that url to anyone I want to...
url becomes extremely locate or url that anyone can play once that's done all the
located for all of the things that I've just published are available to
show you what that looks like what's cool about this measure media services explorer tool
it's got all this stuff baked in already so all the things that
you'd want your disposal here I might want to encrypt that file I might not want
everybody in the world to be able to play it unless they have a license key so I could easily
encrypted or I can make it clear here are the located is right here.
Here's the one for smooth streaming here's the one for mpeg dash here's the one for each
...before here salon for ageless vthree.
Now you might say great you have to hand
...all these located to all these people all around the world depending on which device they have
as long as a quick click the right located on the right devices...playing then I'll get the video and you
would have to say that that's true until just quite recently when something else really
magical came out from our development team and that's what we call the
asher media player as you media player is across platform player
that automatically detects what you are running it on and pulls down the video
...format matches your device.
Don't believe me you can try it for yourself
there's a website aka dot ms-dot amt demo feel free to go to that
anytime you like the idea of course with the asher media player is it
knows what device it's running on so you don't have to do the heavy lifting if you're
running on an android found will pull down the format android can handle if you're running on
...iphone are...pull that down so what I can show you is
...looks like on my laptop here...back?
So, I'm using the actual media player
...internet explorer that's I just went
...played that file that I just published that's what it looks like an...
I can go full-screen of course.
This is an adaptive
...raping question cloud moi.
That's...it looks like moi.
This is a demo website of course is the players on website and
what...I can show you is that I can take the link to this url and I can cut and
paste and put it into another website?
And, show you how the player is portable so I've got a
website running here this is my video collection site is just running and adj
...it's just a silly callwebsite based on orchard if I go into orchard here and I'm going to go
...modify this page.
And, what I'm going to do is I'm going to add
a link to that video that I just published on this page?
Something go ahead and do that...go to the page that's running just the homepage I'm
just going to edit html web page you can always do this on anything here it
is I'll say this is a cruel hollow...video?
But, I just put up in the cloud.
And, at the bottom after that I'm going to cut and
paste my embed code from the player is going to show up as an
I frame and I frame that has the player already attached to it so you know-how everybody
...descending like youtube links around and you email them and you put them on
your facebook why should youtube have all the functionality and also manage all
of your content think of this is a way to get that same functionality but it's your website.
So, now I have my links into my web page and
it comes with the player because it's a hosted player.
All right...the save this and publisher.
Of course that's going to happen right in the middle of my demo.
Ok, now.
Let's go and see what looks like when I go to that web page.
Here's the web page again and now it has the video link.
...displayable bowman somebody else's website is playing out if you
...believe may think that there's some sort of...
doing up my sleeve I've already given you a url so you can try this yourself here this.
Ak dot microsoft build slash build microsoft feel free to do this...if
you're devices the idea here is that the player works on
whatever device you have and you can imbed now videos into all of your
web pages or your web applications really easy the
...solves a huge challenge and what is that challenge well it's been
so hard to be able to put video into your applications because you had to have so many different versions of
replications...to make sure that ram identify lash version and silverlight version maybe had
one for ios maybe add one for android, you know, and,
then your playback was always very complicated but now with the cloud we
solved the little this two things are happening here one is we've got player for
you that plays on any device that you tried on one code plays on all
places html code the second is the cloud auto converts
the format of the video to match the protocol that your device works on we...dynamic
packaging now if you remember from the tool...go ahead and go back to my tool here?
If you notice this but there's a whole lot of urls get...when I
...publish that video file these located...but this is the one
here zoom in on it see this one right here.
This was the only one that I put in that link that length that's the one that I put in
the link on the web page another words we use the our of the player and what we
called dynamic packaging from the cloud to have the cloud auto-detects what device were
playing on and delivery the video in exactly that format this is how you really
can simplify your development efforts by only publishing your content
...only encoding your content once?
And, only creating a client once in other words really make it easy
to share video now that video file that I just played...which was that hollow
...video from the from the build show that could have just been
...as easily alive stream cc I could have done exactly the same thing using the
exact same player exact same way to do it and just
...alive video stream into a website that's how easy it is now you gotta do is
start the camera and start the channel running very powerful but
that's exactly what we wanted to do for you guys the developer so.
...switch back to the powerpoint presentation.
So, it's really is all is easy as taking a better code html.
Will javascript throw that into your web page?
And, suddenly giving yourself the our video right away and let the cloud do it all
...that website one more time...get of what I just
showed which was my website just playing the video embed that I showed you and you can play around with that if you like.
And, if you're still looking for that url of the
...media player demo feel free to visit that site you can get there.
...features of the player because this is so new are going to grow over time we've got
quite a lot of things that we're adding now all of these things are coming because of the feedback they were getting from
our developers and our partners you are telling us what are some of the cool features...the player that you'd
...to add and...adding that into the into the capabilities so as we move their time
we just-released this only couple weeks ago is brand-new the player the
...media player hoping...take advantage of it take a look at it and
give some feedback...kinds of things you'd like us to add it works on all manner
of browsers devices.
And, also supports encrypted content and that's very important
...as we all know that are content is valuable for some people in the industry,
you know, the content is the most valuable thing that you have so you don't want to just
willingly published everywhere you might have business logical rules about who should be able to see it
and they might want to sell your content
...the case with some of the sporting events entertainment content that we work with all the time
the ability to encrypt your content is very important that's part of what we offer
...services all right let's move on to something else maybe
you heard about our new media intelligence features within
measure media services were released approximate faulk of the
...media index...this is really awesome technology.
Part of what we've done is taking the same technology that's been built into products like
the digital assistant core tama or perhaps it connect or maybe you used
our new bing translate or scribe translate services or taking the our of speech
or converting into text and that way you can search for your video
libraries for key words that were spoken in the video and what it will be able to do is help you
...database so that your application
your search application can use video assets the same way you might excel spreadsheets are word
...to find keywords?
Off-course has to work in multiple languages so we...now
...english and spanish with...like chinese and
japanese german italian french portuguese all of them are going to come now what does this look
like so I'll give you an idea of what this technology looks like as well...switch back.
So, here we have my friend joe who's doing a hollow...presentation and when I did is I took
his video and I submitted it to our index are?
Now how do I do that you might ask
well before we get too far in the demo wind...show you where that lives.
Here is the video that I uploaded and look right here index the asset with
asset media casually index are of course in api for
its that to when I kick that off it will begin to index that video file right
away and produce for me the entire transcript of the spoken words that were in a video
automatically the accuracy is pretty good it's about ninety to ninety five
percent accurate that's not a hundred-percent perfect that's a pretty far way down the path of
you transcribing automatically all of the video content.
So, I'm...play the video file you can see is the index
or just went through the video file line-by-line.
And, created the closed captioning track the index
track with the time-code associated with it and...dumped all of this
file all...this data into a file that looks like this
xml file with the track itself which is completely edible so
if there were words that joe said that we didn't recognize well that's okay because you can go back
in edit later now you might think well that's really fascinating
that certainly saving a lot of time I was able to quickly index...create the closed captioning
track for all my videos but what can I actually do with that you might ask...answer
for you take science cinema this is run by one of the government science labs
in the united states they've taken about a thousand or ten thousand videos and they have
index their entire video content library are all science videos about astronomy
or astrophysics so they often have a lot of requests from their constituents and the people who
use the service for particular videos about particular topics make sense
...research institution we have so many videos how do, you know,
...in the video those particular topics are let's just say,
for example, I was interested in looking for all the videos that had the phrase binary pulsar in
it because I'm doing a paper on
...I need to find information about that.
Well, what this does a search for the entire library
they've got and pulls out for me all of videos that have the word binary pulsar
in it now that's interesting but then I have to watch the whole video
no I sure don't because of the way that the index
are works I can jump right to the part of the video where that person is going to
speak and say that thing that I'm looking for which is the binary pulsar and
the player which they've embedded into their website here we'll just play that part of the video?
So, you get the idea you can build pretty impressive video content
video applications that search and say exactly what the content with
the viewer wants you to...really helps you personalize
your video content library now this technology this
indexing technology can not only just do words.
Today but in the future imagine
what we're adding hopefully...future builds I'll be able to show you this facial detection
...people inside your video or maybe image detection I want to find a particular
graphic or logo inside my video or...about sound effects the sound of
the gun shop or maybe eiffel tower just imagine if
video is just as easily search through is every other type of document that we keep its share
and that's precisely what this is really all about bringing media
intelligence and content enhancements and metadata to the video content that
...that you use on a regular basis.
Now live-streaming I talked about that when I open as I said
...channel nine has been broadcasting and streaming the build
conference this week and they've been doing actually...services to do it a check out
their website and you'll see what I'm talking about now what were the necessary components
in order to make that happen if I walk through that with you so you can get take a look at this.
The first thing of...you have to get your content to the cloud.
The your live content to the cloud so we have really enhance the
attributed services platform this year.
Today you can now send to us any of the following types of content any live
streams in these formats and...be able to receive them and process them so
...very common format for sending live video
...the cloud or you can create encoded with microsoft's...streaming or what's called
fragmented mp for or you can take the new approach which we just announced a few
weeks ago which is our tp or mpeg transport streams of course this is the
format that most broadcasters use around the world today when they distribute content
you can now take a live feed in mpeg transport send
...the cloud and now take advantage of something we just announced which is called
cloud live encoding this now it takes the ability of
doing the encoding in the cloud itself instead of...having to have a device
...outside the cloud.
Piece of hardware or software that does it for you now this
is really awesome when you're talking about trying to do lots of channels
that come and go like the sort of sporting events like I've talked about or
a medical conference...conference like this so you can easily spin up a
cloud virtual live encoder run it encoder live-streaming and a
...over destroy the virtual encoder and it's gone you don't have to
have physical assets physical encoders that you're carrying around racking and stacking
is pretty impressive and the capabilities...cloud live encoder
...exactly what broadcasters and developers like yourself we
think we really need the...to multiple layers a video multi bit rates the
ability to audio to...do closed captioning to meet
compliance standards and government standards and if you're so inclined you can certainly do ad
...to place advertisements and slates inside your video have
various ad breaks all of that is capable now through the
cloud no longer do you have to have a physical device to do this.
As I mention of course live-streaming wouldn't work so well if you could only
stream into one kind of device therefore...services cloud supports
them all four major protocols for streaming video.
Adaptive...are supported
by this cloud so appalachia less which also allows you to go to ios
android devices as well as many smart tv's mpeg dash which of course is the new
...ts standard for video streaming microsoft smooth streaming
format is continuous will continue to be supported and even adobe https for flash
base content so you see we support all of the different methodology
for streaming so you can have the widest audience possible and then
of course live wouldn't be as vat valuable if you just always gave it
away for free therefore you can encrypt your content to protected and
only enabled allow those people who are authorized to
...stream to see your content because they require license key to descriptive
of course we didn't stop there we had to keep enhancing and that's precisely
what we've done so in addition the fact that we can scale these...
servers these streaming servers to meet an audience of whatever size audience you can attract
their content whether you're talking about a small audience of
a few doctors to millions of people who might be watching the world cup or the
superbowl or the olympic games which of course we did in so tty russia
your so ago and will again...but there's also some great features that we think make this really
exciting compelling as a developer I'm sure you can take you would love to take advantage of them
...called instantaneous live to vad and cloud dvr how does this work well
imagine you're broadcasting hockey game now
...viewer most of us like to try to watch the game and,
we don't like to enter the game late but...unavoidable sometimes we join life program
in progress and we've just missed it but, with the our of cloud I want the ability to back
it up to join in the second-quarter and go back to the first the first period
of the first-quarter and watch the hockey game from the start I can do this because the cloud
automatically buffers the stream of your live events and turns it into
an on-demand asset so that your viewers if you
want to give it to them can instantly watch it at their pace at their
schedule including ability to pause live tv now most of you might be thinking the sounds very tivo
...of course it but there's no tivo involved...using the cloud to do it and you
have that capability when you use...services to build...takes advantage of...services?
Now there's another part I want to also demonstrate to you guys today and this is something that
we called dynamic manifest creation which I kind of affectionately re terms
...clipping what is this is the ability to take a
live-streaming that's running and take highlight from a
really key exciting moment from it and make it available to be
viewed by somebody else without them having to jump define that moment in your
life stream in other words I'll give you an example I'll go back to the laptop to do it.
So, here I have a...clipper tool.
And,...recognize the same hollow
...video asset that I've put in here right out just bear
with me imagine that this wasn't in fact a video asset that I pre-recorded but the
...stream maybe of the keynote that just happened yesterday the day before
so this kind of tool will enable need a clip out a moment and send that and
say that and share that with my friends so live-streaming playing here
is and then something really awesome happens like I don't
know this really cool view of...sitting on the table.
Yeah, I know this is all not so exciting but maybe you want something a little bit
more exciting irate let's jump out of holland we've probably seen enough of
...this week let's go to something more exciting like I don't know
about soccer soccer's
always very exciting there we go so let's say that this live event is going
...it's a soccer game and something really awesome happens like wow.
You know, a goal that goal was so amazing I as the owner of
the stream want to share this with my friends so I'm going to...that point
it point in time in my life stream which I'm going to start and let that run for a
little bit and see when the end of my highlighted moment is.
...was a great moments that
...a great moment that was a great moment okay that's good enough.
Set out what...I done just
...ten seconds of my life stream or of my video asset that I want to share and now
what do I do well go down here and just get rid of the a task bar here.
I'm going to
go in here and type in great moments in soccer.
And, I grab and image.
...thumbnail...publisher.
Now this tool is just an example of
how you could create a clip from a live stream.
And, this clip doesn't really exist
...creating a virtual clip a virtual
clip that is completely...here's my clip
all play my ten second clip right see the time meters now only ten
seconds the...is a clip
...live stream might still be happening that soccer game might still be happening but, you know,
what I can't wait for that live event to be over I want to share this really
highlighted magic moment with you so I'm going to take this and...to create
url and...always has been carefully choose and salute...
All right here's the url of my clip.
I'm just showing it you can see it now what do you notice
really interesting about this bit right here zoom in.
This thing called filter name what I've done is use the cloud to create a dynamic filter a
dynamic clip of a video acid that still running with the time indicator that tells
it and when I share this video clip with you I can I can send it
to-you if I want what I do that go back to my friendly neighborhood
...media player if I stick the url in the player and play it?
Here's my clips when except the other clip is still running in the background physical...
Here you go there's my clip right moi.
And, now if I go back to the beginning of the demo remember I just can
could take this and I can send this url to all of you.
I can email that and now my
clip is even twice as good...not only a clip of alive image alive stream
...happen but now it's a player that plays the live clip on any device that I
scented...if I were to texas all...right now all of you just this one
clip I don't have to know what device you're using I just sent you a clip from a
...stream an interest in played on a device any device that's
...the player gives you so you see what I've combined is all of
these technologies together to give you the owner of this live stream
...amazing ability to share highlights of...streams with your audience
now you can use this from marketing you could...to really promote right or you
could use it to really build a social environment around,
around your content imagine what this might mean if you're building
applications for sharing videos exchanging videos and not just the whole
video but bits of the video the best parts of video so all of this everything I've just
show you all available today through developer api
...or through tools like that some clipper tool that I just showed you which is also
just using api is just built around a way free to see it.
Now of course live-streaming wouldn't be good if you could measure it you couldn't distributed around
the world and that's part of what we...we conclude with so when you when you create
these live events it doesn't matter where the live event is happening if
your audiences around the world you can do that what how is it possible why is
that so easy because very simply I can say I
want my stream to be made available globally and we have quite literally
just recently added a small little check box inside a measurement services on the
...management portal that allows you to add what's called the content delivery network a
cds and all you have to do is say I want my streams
to automatically go through...so they can globally distributed and this gives you the
powered hit all these dots and all the surrounding miles and hundreds of miles
around the dots that your audiences can grow and grow and grow you
can hit your...send your content wherever you want and will be adding more and more and
more these dots as we microsoft continues to do interconnects with third-party
partners all around the world so that you can stream your video content from
high high-definition including four-k all the way down to
low bit rates on cell phones
...three-g forging networks wherever your viewers happen to be so that's kind
of the our of using the cloud to distribute your content especially if it's life?
Now in a little bit my colleague...is going to share with you a little bit more about how to do some
of these things how the live-streaming data flow works.
And, the idea of course here is that.
All the components of the cloud now exists and all the components of the
...are available for-you so-if you want-to spin up a
brand-new channel set up a webcam send that webcam up to the
to the cloud whether that webcam is able to spit out a format that's
...encoded or maybe it's a camera that's not doing pre encoding you want use the
cloud to encoded you can now send your content up to the cloud and do the live encoding
from there you can distribute perhaps by encryption to our streaming endpoints
and those streaming endpoints will...who or what device
is watching your content so...convert your content...multitude of different streaming protocols
...can player content any device that's in the market today of course if you want to
encrypt that content why shouldn't you
so you encrypted and you set up a license a
license delivery mechanism and we do that as well that's already provided as part imagine
media services...quite a lot of detail around how to use...content protection mechanisms so
you can encrypt your content and use the cloud to distribute license keys license
keys that will always be available if the person who's watching and wants to
watcher content is so authorized to do that and that's critical
of course because now that means that you have full control and you can integrate with
...systems are active directory if you want by doing token exchange and our to say to
someone you should or should not be able to watch my content so part of putting your
...the cloud is all about protecting the content distributing that
...but most importantly making that content is easily accessible and viewable and
...by you...other kind of
document or file or any kind of mechanism that we use and asher today that's the idea with
attributed services so I'm going to sort of conclude with that...
will take some questions at the end but I want to thank you very much for joining
this overview session today andI would invite you to take a look at any of the different
asher resources that are that are available about the build conference and certainly
...in the things that I've just talked about their all available for you to try for free get yourself and asher
account and just find that button in the management...says as your media services
creative media services count and off you go and whether you're going to use the developer tool the
explore tool that I just showed you to upload encode
encrypt index and publisher content or you want to do all that yourself through dot
net or java or build an application that really maps to your need if you want to
incorporate and...player app so that you don't have to build the client app you can do that but if
you're so inclined we have...case that help you write apps for ios
android windows as well so hopefully we've got everything
...you need to really get your video content out there published
...viewable and really,
really make the cloud work for your video applications I hope that this
has been helpful please don't forget to send us your feedback and...and...and,
some comments on how we've done and I'm very much thank you is there any questions I'd be happy to take them about
as you media services or any of the things that I've shown...so thank you very much?
This...image I can
right I have a question about the live-streaming coding the for a few months ago I try
...encode with the open...software.
And, it didn't work because the asher...requires
a few parameters like did gop.
Is still error...
To encode I'm sorry is the...
our requirement now yes we have all kinds of formats that we can except I think I
listed the three in one of my previous slides so you send in...
mp and there's set of configurations that you have to come your...mph stream has to comply with you
can send...microsoft smooth and...we have that and now the new art cp which of course will do
the encoding not on your local device but on prime so I'd be happy to show
you about all this information is available through our after media blog which
is often measure dot com slash media but all the information need to configure your
live stream or your stream is there and you just configure and if you're doing your
pre encoding yourself or you want use...new cloud based encoders you?
Okay, so,...it does support the will
...open broadcast software I don't know
...that one in particular but if the protocol
supports the three that we supported then we can take that stream from that supports
...should be good engine will be happy to work with you if...it's not quite work out for
youanother question from the player.
Does it support chrome just?
Doesn't run comcast, yeah, no, I mean like
...groupm just...question I don't know if that's if that's our list
...to go back and like the idea of courses that
it should run on every browser type that's available today and chrome is certainly one of
them so let's take a look and we'll find out and off the top ahead?
All hang around for a little bit thank you very much I hope you'll stick around and
...my colleague in about two five one
...to, yeah,
so, please stick around and enjoying her for a deeper divx and take a look at how you can code and
develop this stuff but...you and enjoy the rest of your build and...safe...